Rohit Raghav

Faridabad, Haryana, India ☑ rohitraghav1296@gmail.com ☐ 8802292366

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with 5+ years of progressive experience in the IT industry, involved in complete SDLC including analysis, design, development, testing, support and maintenance of enterprise level web applications. Proven ability to troubleshoot and debug software problems.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Mercer | Mettl

March 2022 - Present, Gurgaon, India

- Active Participant in Daily scrum, Sprint planning, retrospective meetings with QA, Product team, Business Head.
- Responsible for upgrading microservices from Spring to Spring Boot.
- Developed a real-time streaming platform that enabled low-latency data processing.
- Responsible for creation of REST APIs and Microservices.
- Strategically reduced cost of AWS Cloud upto 25%.
- Involved in the code promotion using CI/CD pipeline.
- Responsible for fixing OWASP vulnerabilities like XSS, CSRF, SQL Injection and Referrer Policy.
- Ensured Adhoc releases with subject of critical data movements.

Software Engineer

Country Delight

November 2021 - March 2022, Gurgaon, India

- Integrated payment gateway into the web application that allowed for secure online payments.
- Developed Auto Pay feature for better customer experience.
- Used Graph based libraries for creating serviceable zones.
- Involved in migration from monolithic to Micro services architecture.
- Responsible for developing RESTful APIs related to Products, Customer and Orders.

Software Developer 2

Mercer | Mettl

May 2019 - November 2021, Gurgaon, India

- Proficient in POC, Development, Dev testing and Resolving Prod Bugs by giving Hot Fixes.
- Involved in analysis of business requirements and validation rules and closely working with on-site people for understanding their business requirements.
- Ensured best performance by analysing issues and fixing bugs reported by QA and Product.
- Created PostgreSQL schema using Liquibase for an utility application.
- Monitoring activity logs for services on staging and production.
- Designed and Developed Node.js app with AWS Lambda, S3 and SQS to generate assessment certificates.

Software Developer

CFE India Private Ltd

July 2018 - May 2019, Gurgaon, India

- Developed RESTful APIs for integrating front end app with backend application.
- Designed and Developed Single Page Application using Angular.
- Developed Microservices using Node.js.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Maharishi Dayanand University • Rohtak, Haryana • 2018

SKILLS

Java, Spring Boot, JPA, AWS Cloud, Kafka, Docker, SQL, GIT, JIRA, Maven, Redis, MongoDB, Liquibase, Microservices, JSP